A Finding Aid to the World House Galleries records, 1927-1991, bulk 1953-1980, in the Archives of American Art AAA.worlhoug
Archives of American Art
World House Galleries records
bulk 1953-1980
1927-1991
AAA.worlhoug
Archives of American Art
9.8 Linear feet 11 boxes, 1 OV
The records of New York City World House Galleries measure 9.8 linear feet and date from 1927 to 1991, with the bulk of them dating from 1953 to 1980. The collection documents the gallery's general business affairs, sales, and relationships with artists from 1953-1968, and later gifts and sales by founder entrepreneur and art collector Herbert Mayer. Artists for which files are found include Jean Dubuffet, Ernst Ludwig Kirchner, Paul Klee and Georgio Morandi, among many others. Additional records include correspondence, inventory records, sales and purchase records, records of gifts and auctions, and shipping and consignment records.
World House Galleries
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 7 series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1962-1987 (0.8 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 2: Artist Files, 1927-1991 (4.6 linear feet; Box 1-6, 11, OV 12)
Series 3: Inventory Records, 1953-1986 (0.6 linear feet; Box 6)
Series 4: Sales & Purchases, 1956-1987 (0.4 linear feet; Box 6-7)
Series 5: Gifts, 1970-1987 (0.6 linear feet; Box 7, 11, OV 12)
Series 6: Auctions, 1956-1959, 1968-1988 (1.4 linear feet; Box 7-9, 11)
Series 7: Shipping Statements, 1958, 1968-1986 (1.4 linear feet; Box 9-10)
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Scope and Contents note
The records of New York City World House Galleries measure 9.8 linear feet and date from 1927 to 1991, with the bulk of the records dating from 1953 to 1980. The collection documents the gallery's general business affairs, sales, and relationships with artists from 1953-1968, and later gifts and sales by founder entrepreneur and art collector Herbert Mayer. Artists for which files are found include Jean Dubuffet, Ernst Ludwig Kirchner, Paul Klee and Georgio Morandi, among many others. Additional records include correspondence, inventory records, sales and purchase records, records of gifts and auctions, and shipping and consignment records.
Correspondence is somewhat scattered and concerns administrative matters and business with galleries, collectors, museums, and a few artists.
Artist files contain a variety of documents, such as correspondence, artist statements and resumes, sales records, printed materials, and photographs about artists who were either represented by World House Galleries or in whom the gallery was interested. Artists for which files are found include Jean Dubuffet, Ernst Ludwig Kirchner, Paul Klee and Georgio Morandi, among many others.
Inventory records include art inventory lists and notes, provenance documentation, and consignment records. Also found are financial records of sales and of purchases made abroad and within the United States.
Documents about Herbert Mayer’s donations to Colgate University and other organizations and institutions, including the Art Students League and Parsons School of Design are in the Gifts series. These records include correspondence, printed materials, and copies of agreements and forms.
Auction records are found for sales through Christie's, Sotheby’s and Parke-Bernet auction houses of World House Galleries art inventory, and Herbert Mayer's personal art collection. This series contains photographs of art, auction catalogs, correspondence, and other miscellaneous materials.
Shipping files contain documents such as statements, customs forms, and correspondence about shipments of art from around the world, mostly from Europe, to World House Galleries.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The World House Galleries records were donated in 2002 by Herbert Mayer, Jr., son of gallery founder Herbert Mayer.
Biographical/Historical note
World House Galleries was founded by Herbert Mayer, Sr. in 1953 in New York City. The gallery operated until 1968, representing an eclectic group of artists from around the world.
Herbert Mayer (circa 1911-1993) was a lawyer, businessman and owner of the World House Galleries in New York City. He attended Colgate University in Hamilton, New York where he majored in English and graduated in 1929. After graduation, he traveled through Europe with Colgate English Professor Russell Speirs and the four months he spent in Paris studying art at the Louvre was a formative experience for Mayer. He went on to attend law school at the University of Wisconsin. He was lawyer in New York until the early 1940s, then began selling television sets which were more familiar to the U.S. public after the 1939 World’s Fair. In 1944, Mayer stopped practicing law and became a television magnate. He founded the Empire Coil Company, which manufactured radiofrequency coils for television sets and stations. From 1949 through 1952, Mayer launched television stations in Cleveland, Ohio; Portland, Oregon; and Kansas City, Missouri.
In 1953, Mayer bid farewell to the world of television and founded the World House Galleries. The gallery was located on Madison Avenue in New York City’s Carlyle Hotel, occupying a total of 6,900 square feet on two floors. Architect Frederick Kiesler was commissioned to design the space. Mayer’s goal was to attract a wider audience to contemporary international art and, in his words, “express the thinking and feeling of contemporary artists everywhere — wherever unusual talent is discovered.” Mayer worked closely with Colgate Professor Alfred Krakusin, who became the gallery advisor, and the two frequently traveled together in search of new art. On his trips abroad, Mayer also purchased art for his personal collection.
World House Galleries represented an eclectic group of European artists such as Jean Dubuffet, Ernst Ludwig Kirchner, Paul Klee and Georgio Morandi in addition to lesser known artists. World House Galleries exhibitions included art for sale within the gallery, as well as art loaned from private collections and museums. The gallery represented an eclectic group of artists from Austria, France, Finland, Greece, Iceland, Italy, Norway, Spain and Sweden. Mayer and Krakusin also collaborated on Sculptura, a business which created bronze casts of statues and plaques to be sold at the gallery.
World House Galleries had strong ties with Colgate University and Mayer arranged numerous exhibitions at his alma mater between 1956 and 1962. The exhibitions were held in the basement of Lawrence Hall and showcased art from World House Galleries and Mayer’s personal collection. In 1958, Mayer donated the first of many gifts of art to Colgate University. His largest gift of almost 2000 paintings, sculptures, and drawings occurred in 1967 and became the core collection for what is now known as Colgate’s Picker Art Gallery.
After World House Galleries closed in 1968 Herbert Mayer continued to sell art through auction houses and galleries as well as make donations to Colgate and various other organizations through the 1980s. In early 1971, Mayer contacted Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. to arrange an auction of artwork from his personal collection. The bulk of his collection was sold through Parke-Bernet in 1984.
Mayer died in 1991, survived by his wife, Bet, and their five children. Through exhibitions which showcased art from different countries, World House Galleries exposed the New York art world to a more diverse vision of international modernism.
Art Students League (New York, N.Y.); Christie, Manson & Woods International Inc..; Colgate University.; Dubuffet, Jean, 1901-; Kirchner, Ernst Ludwig, 1880-1938; Klee, Paul, 1879-1940; Mayer, Herbert, 1908-1991; Morandi, Giorgio, 1890-1964; Parke-Bernet Galleries.; Parsons School of Design ##naf; Sotheby's (Firm); Art galleries, Commercial -- New York (State) -- New York; Photographs
- Correspondence, 1962-1987; Series 1; 0.8 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of somewhat scattered business and administrative correspondence with clients, collectors, museums, galleries, auction houses, and a few artists. Correspondence concerns art purchases, loans to other galleries, and requests for Mayer to view art or visit artist studios. Some of the correspondence includes attached artist resumes. There is some additional correspondence scattered throughout the collection.
  - Albert Loeb and Krugier Gallery, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Arnoldi, Angelika, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bilotti, Carlo F., 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Blue Moon Gallery, Inc., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bourdelle, Rhodia Dufet, 1968; 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bruni, Claudio, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Carter, James, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chapius, Maurice, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Christie's, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Conte, Pino, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Couturier, Marion B., 1967-1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Des Moines Art Center, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Emily Lowe Gallery, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Eva Lee Gallery, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Feingarten Galleries, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fidell-Beaufort, Madeleine, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Finch College Museum of Art, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fischer, Marie-Claude, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - French & Company, Inc., 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Gaehde, Christa M., 1971-1972; 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Galerie Drouant, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Galerie Krugier et Cie., 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Gatch, Lee and Elsie, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Geist, Sidney, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Giannaccini, Gino, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Glezer Art Gallery, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Goldschmidt, Lucien, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Goldsmith, Herman C., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Gottlieb, Carla, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Grandini, Sergio, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Greenwich Auction Room, Ltd., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Harriet Griffin Gallery, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Heise, Bill, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Hirschl & Adler, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Howard Beilin, Inc., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Jackson Pollock Catalogue Raisonne, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Joseph H. Hirshhorn Museum, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Kornfeld und Klipstein, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Kunthaus Lempertz, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Lauck, Anthony J., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Lee Ault & Company, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Magriel, Paul, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Martini, Quinto, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Musee Rodin, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Music, Zoran, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - "M" Miscellaneous, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Nash, David, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - National Collection of Fine Arts, 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - National Gallery of Art, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Neikrug Galleries, Inc., 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Ny Carlsberg Glyptothek, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Odyssia Gallery, 1979-1980; 1969 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Perez, Maria Guzman, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Rare Art, Inc., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Raun, Joanna, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Rodin Museum, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Rothschild Fine Arts, Inc., 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Serge Sabersky Gallery, Inc., 1972-1987 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Shankar's International Children's Competition, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Sotheby's, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Spink & Son Ltd., 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Spyropoulos, Jannis and Zoe, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Staempfli Gallery, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Stephen Hahn Gallery, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Strauss, Mrs. Leonard, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - "S" Miscellaneous, 1968-1983 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Tamari, S., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Vancouver Art Gallery, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Veisbrot, Boris, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - "V" Miscellaneous, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Weidler, Charlotte, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Weintraub Gallery, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Yampolsky, Phyllis, circa 1973 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Zetterberg, Johan, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Zhang, Yue, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Artist Files, bulk 1950-1980; 1927-1991; Series 2; 4.6 Linear feet Box 1-6, 11, OV 12
  Artist files contain a variety of material on artists who were represented by World House Galleries or in whom the gallery was interested. Artist files hold correspondence, artist statements and resumes, sales records, printed materials, and exhibition catalogs. Most of the files also include images of the artist and of the artist's work in the form of slides, transparencies, negatives, and photographs. Prominent artists represented by the gallery and for which files exist include Jean Dubuffet, Ernst Ludwig Kirchner, Paul Klee and Georgio Morandi, in addition to many artists from around the world.
  - Australian Aboriginal Art, circa 1949-1957 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Acquarani, Miguel, 1952-circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Affandi, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Ajmone, Giuseppe, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Alexandrakis, Maria (Vryakos), circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Alliot, L., circa 1953-1968 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Amat, Jose, circa 1955-1968 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Angelo, Domenick, circa 1953-1968 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Aperghis, Achille, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Arp, Jean, circa 1961 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Åström, Werner, circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Bacci, Edmundo, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Baizerman, Saul, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Banchieri, Giuseppe, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Bertram, Abel, 1942-1961 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Biennale di Venezia (Venice Biennial), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 1.
  - Bissier, Julius, circa 1959 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Bissiere, Roger, circa 1961 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Björklund, Poul, 1953-1967 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Blondal, Gunlag, 1953-1968 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Borsato, Renato, circa 1957 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Börje, Gideon, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Bosch Roger, Emilio, circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Boucher, Francois, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Boudin, Eugene, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Bourdelle, Emile-Antoine, 1956-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bourdelle, Emile-Antoine #167 shipment, 1987-1991; 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bourdelle, Emile-Antoine #490 shipment, 1967; 1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bourdelle Museum, circa 1957 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Brancaccio, Giovanni, circa 1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Braun-Giesenfeld, Greta von, circa 1955 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Breidvik, Arne, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bueno, Antonio, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Campigli, Massimo, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cantatore, Domenico, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Capmany, Ramon de, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Capogrossi, Giuseppe, circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Carmelo, Zotti, circa 1957 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Caro, Anthony, circa 1957 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Carriere, Eugene, circa 1962 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cassinari, Bruno, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Cederstrom, Eva, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Chadwick, Lynn, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Chagall, Marc, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Challou, Jacques-Gabriel, circa 1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Charmy, Emilie, circa 1962 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Chubac, Albert, circa 1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Ciangottini, Giovanni, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Coignard, James, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Coin Collection, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Conejo, Andres, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Consagra, Pietro, circa 1958 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Conte, Pino, 1956-1964 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Cooke, Barrie, circa 1961 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Corot, Jeanne, circa 1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Cortes, Francisco, circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Courbet, Gustave, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - D'Aloisio da Vasto, Carlo, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - D'Arena, Francesco, circa 1957 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Daderian, Dikra, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Dahl, Cecilie, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Dalla Zorza, Carlo, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Daubigny, C. F., 1974-1987 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 2.
  - Daumier, Honoré, circa 1957 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - De Dardel, Simone, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - De Kat, Ann-Pierre, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - De Maestro, I., circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Degas, Edgar, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Derain, Andre, circa 1962 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Disbhand, Laemsingh, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Drougge, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Dubuffet, Jean, 1959-1965 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 3.
  - Dufour, Bernard, circa 1959 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Dumont, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Durencamps, Rafael, 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Eberl, Francois, 1927-1955 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Eftimiadi-Menegaki, Froso, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - El Greco, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Elson, Diane, circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Engilberts, Jon, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Ernst, Max, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - "Fairy Maiden," Early Ming Painting, 1958; 1982 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Fazzini, Pericle, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Feito, Luis, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Fohlin, B. G., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Foppiani, Gustavo, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Frosterus-Segerstråhle, H., circa 1948 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Friström, Oscar, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Gabritchewsky, Eugene, circa 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Gal, Menchu, circa 1955 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Gatch, Lee, 1961-1988 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Gauguin, Eugene Henri Paul Drawings, 1959; 1973-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Gauguin, Eugene Henri Paul Sketchbook Cover, circa 1924 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gauguin, Paul René, 1969-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Paul René Gauguin is the grandson of the French Impressionist Eugene Henri Paul Gauguin.
  - Gebhard, Johannes, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gentilini, Franco, 1952-1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Giacometti, Alberto, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Giandante, circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Gianoukakis, Dimitrios, circa 1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Gilioli, Emile, 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 4.
  - Godi, Goffredo, 1951-1956 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gonzalez, Paloma, 1953-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Greco, Emilio, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Oversized material housed in OV 12.
  - Greek Artists, 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Greek Artists Photographs, A-M, circa 1940-1956 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Greek Artists Photographs, N-Z, circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Guerin, A. M., 1987 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Guidi, Virgilio, 1953-1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Guijarro, Antonio, 1953-1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Guillermo, Juan, 1951-circa 1955 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Haalke, Hjalmar, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Harpignies, 1953-1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Haupt, Matti, 1956; 1965 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Heerup, Henry, circa 1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Hoflehner, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Huet, Anne-Marie, circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Hurum, Per, circa 1955 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - "Idka" (Ida Cohen), circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Imai, Toshimatsu, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Istrati, Dumitresco, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Jacque, Maurice, circa 1955 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Jansem, Jean, 1954-circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Jorn, Asger, circa 1975 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Kallos, Paul, circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Kanerva-Sirola, Kaino, circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Kapralos, Christos, 1953-1956 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Kay, Archibald, circa 1953-1968 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Kemeny, Zoltan, 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Kiesler, Frederick, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Kihlman, Einar, circa 1945 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Klee, Paul, 1958-1987 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Klibi, Naceur, circa 1959 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Kokoschka, Oskar, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Kopman, Benjamin, circa 1957 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Kosta, Alex, 1973-1986 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Lanskoy, André Mikhailovitch, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Lapayese Bruna, José, 1953-1968 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Lapayese (Del Rio), José, circa 1954 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Lapayese (del Rio), Ramon, circa 1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Lapoujade, Robert, circa 1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Le Persan, Raffy, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Licata, Riccardo, circa 1957 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Llimona, Rafael, circa 1957 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Louttre, Marc-Antoine, circa 1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Lucatello, Albino, circa 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Lura, Sverre, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Macarron, Ricardo, 1953-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Macris, Constantin, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Maillel, circa 1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Majorowicz, Roger L., 1962-1956 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Makarona, Nitsa; Miliadis, D.; Mitarakis, John, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Mallo, Cristino, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mallol-Suazo, J. M., circa 1965 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Mannucci, Giannetto, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Manzu, Giacomo, 1956-1961 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Maragopoulou, Koula, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Marcucci, Mario, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Martini, Quinto, circa 1958 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Mascherini, Marcello, 1958-1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Mazzullo, Giuseppe, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Meckseper, Freidrich, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Merton, Erling, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Mezerova, Julie W., circa 1955 (Box 4)
  - Mikola, Nandor, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Monet, Claude, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Monte, M. G., circa 1959 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Monticelli, Adolphe, 1959-1985 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Moore, Henry, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Morandi, Giorgio, 1956-1966 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Morandis, Gino, circa 1962 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Moyano, Luis, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Munch, Edvard, 1982; 1958-1965 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Munoz, Julian Perez, 1953-1968 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Music, Antonio, circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Negri, Mario, circa 1958 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 5.
  - Nellimarka, Eero, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Nicolaou, Nicolaos, circa 1948-1952 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Nolde, Emil, circa 1965 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Novillo, Martinez, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Nybo, Claus, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Ochoa, Luis Garcia, circa 1955 (Box 4, Folder 43-44)
  - Ollivary, Annette, 1956-1959 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Orjavuono, Iris, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Palencia, Benjamin, circa 1954 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Pan, Marta, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Paolucci, Giorgio Dario, 1954-1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Parker, Robert Andrew, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Pattison, Abbott, circa 1961 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Perizi, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Picasso, Pablo, 1957-1961 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Planson, 1953-1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Poliakoff, Serge, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Polycandriotis, Antonios, circa 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Pomodoro, Arnoldo and Gio, 1957-1963 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 6-7.
  - Porliefsson, Jon, 1953-1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Poulain, Michel-Marie, circa 1955 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Powell, Fred, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Prado, Marina Nunez del, 1952-1966 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Ramous, Carlo, 1956-1966 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Reder, Bernard, circa 1965 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Reggiani, Mauro, circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Reichel, Hans, circa 1959 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Renoir, Pierre-Auguste, circa 1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 8.